<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Chicago Guide</string>

    <string name="category_restaurants">Restaurants</string>

    <!-- Category name for the vocabulary words for colors [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_museum">Museums</string>

    <!-- Category name for the vocabulary words for numbers [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_parks">Parks</string>

    <!-- Category name for the vocabulary words for family members [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_hotels">Hotels</string>


    <string-array name="nameofMuseums">
        <item>The Field Museum</item>
        <item>Chicago History Museum</item>
        <item>Museum of Contemporary Photography</item>
        <item>Art Institute of Chicago</item>
        <item>Museum of Science and Industry</item>
        <item>Adler Planetarium</item>
        <item>The Oriental Institute Museum</item>
        <item>Smart Museum of Art</item>
        <item>Museum of Contemporary Art</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="descriptionOfMuseum">
        <item>Originally founded to house the biological and anthropological collections assembled for the World\’s Columbian Exposition of 1893,
            this massive natural history museum still packs them in with more than 30 permanent exhibitions covering 300,000 square feet.
            Guests come from all around the world to see towering dinos,
            marvel at ancient artifacts from a royal Egyptian tomb or relax in a Chinese rock garden hidden inside the Cyrus Tang Hall of China.</item>
        <item>Formerly known as the Chicago Historical Society,
            this lively museum commemorates the past through the exhibitions that explore historical figures like Abraham Lincoln and local delicacies like the Chicago-style hot dog.
            Guests can climb aboard a vintage "El" car in "Chicago: Crossroads of America" or gaze at lithographs of the city that were created in the 1860s.
            If you\'re working on a project that draws on the history of Chicago,
            you can register for access to the museum\'s Research Library,
            which houses thousands of photographs, publications and artifacts that document the city\'s history.</item>
        <item>Stop scrolling through Instagram and
            check out some of the amazing shots that line the walls of the Museum of Contemporary Photography.
            Founded by Columbia College Chicago,
            the Loop-based gallery hosts around six shows each year,
            including groundbreaking new work made by artists around the globe as well as archival prints from the institution\'s archives.
            It doesn\'t take long to see everything on display in this relatively small museum,
            which makes it a perfect place to experience a bit of culture during your lunch break.</item>
        <item>One of the city\'s most well-known cultural buildings—thanks to the iconic pair of bronze lions,
            that flank grand steps leading up to the entrance—the Art Institute of Chicago is just as impressive once you make your way inside.
            With more than 300,000 artworks in its permanent collection,
            you\'ll find thousands of paintings, sculptures, photos and drawings displayed throughout a sprawling complex of galleries
            and halls.
            If you\'re a first-time guest, make a beeline for Georges Seurat\’s A Sunday on La Grande Jatte
            and the contemporary collection in the Modern Wing.
            Returning visitors can explore the Thorne Miniatures Rooms in the museum\'s basement,
            as well as traveling exhibits devoted to the likes of Andy Warhol and Van Gogh.</item>
        <item>Packed with exhibits that allow you to step inside a simulated tornado or navigate a maze lined with mirrors,
            the Museum of Science and Industry has no shortage of interactive bells and whistles that will appeal to younger visitors.
            Even if you graduated high school decades ago, displays featuring a restored U-505 German submarine,
            a simulated coal mine and a recreation of a Chicago street,
            circa 1910, might make you feel like you\'re on a school field trip again—not to mention
            the fact that you\'re walking through a building that was originally created for the 1893 World\'s Columbian Exposition.</item>
        <item>Blast off on a journey through the stars at the Adler Planetarium,
            where the domed Grainger Sky Theater projects super-high-resolution video
            on an expansive screen that immerses you in the cosmos.
            Elsewhere, you\'ll find exhibitions devoted to manned moon missions,
            the solar system and the history of the universe.</item>
        <item>You\'ll feel like Indiana Jones when you step into this small
            but formidable University of Chicago–run archaeological treasure trove.
            Going as far back as 6,000 years, artifacts include a fragment of what\’s believed to be the world\’s oldest rug,
            an ancient saddle and various ceramic items such as jugs, bowls and incense burners.
            Also on display are objects from ancient Assyria, Anatolia, Israel, Egypt, Persia and in the Mesopotamian gallery,
            a stunning, hard-to-miss 40-ton human-headed winged bull sculpture from Khorsabad.</item>
        <item>Situated on the University of Chicago campus in Hyde Park,
            the Smart Museum of Art was conceived as an institution where scholars could study the arts and develop exhibitions.
            Today, it\'s open to the public and is home to the college\'s collection of fine art and antiquities,
            including scrolls and ceramics from China as well as contemporary works by the likes of Kerry James Marshall and Andy Warhol.
            Explore exhibits devoted to sprawling installations and local art movements before taking a seat in the museum\'s courtyard sculpture garden.</item>
        <item>Among the largest institutions in the world dedicated to art created post-1950,
            the Museum of Contemporary Art is best known for hosting major touring exhibitions,
            such as a retrospective of Doris Salcedo\'s emotionally charged installations
            and a colorful display of Japanese artist Takashi Murakami\'s work.
            Throughout the MCA\'s galleries, you\'ll also find exhibits dedicated to rising local and international artists.
            Once you\'re finished strolling through the galleries, make sure to exit through the well-curated gift shop.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="addressOfMuseums">
        <item>1400 S Lake Shore Dr Chicago IL 60605</item>
        <item>1601 N Clark St Chicago IL 60614</item>
        <item>600 S Michigan Ave Chicago IL 60605</item>
        <item>111 S Michigan Ave Chicago IL 60603</item>
        <item>5700 S Lake Shore Dr Chicago IL 60637</item>
        <item>1300 S Lake Shore Dr Chicago IL 60605</item>
        <item>1155 E 58th St Chicago</item>
        <item>5550 S Greenwood Ave Chicago IL 60637</item>
        <item>220 E Chicago Ave Chicago</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="hoursOfMuseums">
        <item>Daily 9am–5pm</item>
        <item>Daily 9:30am–4:30pm</item>
        <item>Daily 10am–5pm</item>
        <item>Daily 10:30am–5pm</item>
        <item>Daily 9:30am–4pm</item>
        <item>Daily 9:30am–4pm</item>
        <item>Daily 10am–6pm</item>
        <item>Daily 10am–5pm</item>
        <item>Daily 10am–8pm</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="nameOfParks">
        <item>Millennium Park</item>
        <item>Grant Park</item>
        <item>The 606</item>
        <item>Lincoln Park</item>
        <item>Garfield Park</item>
        <item>Jackson Park</item>
        <item>Maggie Daley Park</item>
        <item>South Shore Cultural Center Park</item>
        <item>Humboldt Park</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="descriptionOfParks">
        <item>This 24.5-acre park might be one of the most popular gathering spots in the city, known for its free concerts,
            famous public art installations and its proximity to the Loop.
            The centerpiece of Millennium Park is the Jay Pritzker Pavilion,
            a flowing Frank Gehry-designed structure that hosts of the city\’s biggest outdoor festivals and concerts.
            You\’ll also find the serene Lurie Garden,
            al fresco dining destination the Park Grill and pedestrian bridges that lead to the Art Institute and Maggie Daley Park.
            Welcome to the hub of Chicago\’s front yard. </item>
        <item>Grant Park\’s 319-acre expanse is a popular destination for residents and tourists alike,
            encompassing notable landmarks such as Millennium Park, the Art Institute of Chicago, Buckingham Fountain and Museum Campus.
            Named for President Ulysses S. Grant, the park frequently hosts festivals, road races and other special events.
            Wherever you happen to end up in the park,
            you\’ll be reminded that you\’re still in the middle of Chicago by the spectacular views of the city\’s skyline. </item>
        <item>A formerly abandoned stretch of elevated railway track that runs through Logan Square, Humboldt Park,
            Wicker Park and Bucktown has found new life as the 606.
            Named after the first three digits in every Chicago zip code,
            the 2.7-mile path provides a quick way to travel east and west on the North Side,
            connecting several parks and public art installations.
            Prepare to dodge strollers, bicycles and residents out for a very slow jog on this popular throughway.</item>
        <item>Lincoln Park was named for the 16th President of the United States shortly after his assassination in 1865.
            The park stretches along the lakeshore and contains the Lincoln Park Zoo,
            the Lincoln Park Conservatory and the Lincoln Park Cultural Center.
            The park itself offers golf courses, baseball fields, a skate park and paths for walking, jogging or biking.</item>
        <item>One of Chicago\'s more prominent parks,
            Garfield Park offers facilities for baseball, boxing, basketball, tennis and swimming and also has a playground,
            fitness center, and paths for jogging, walking and biking</item>
        <item>Designed by famous landscape architects Frederick Law Olmsted and Calvert Vaux,
            Jackson Park became the chosen site for the World\'s Columbian Exposition of 1893.
            Today, the 600-acre park offers golf, baseball, a fitness center, basketball, a playground,
            tennis courts and paths for walking, jogging or biking.</item>
        <item>One of the latest additions to the Chicago Park District,
            Maggie Daley Park pays tribute to the late first lady of the city with 20 acres of recreational opportunity.
            Walk across the BP Pedestrian Bridge from Millennium Park and you\’ll be greeted by a 40-foot climbing wall,
            a quarter-mile skating ribbon and one of the most whimsical playgrounds in the city.
            With facilities fit for kids and adults, this is a park where the entire family can spend the day having fun outdoors</item>
        <item>Located in the South Shore community,
            South Shore Cultural Center is a cultural facility that has been recognized as a Chicago Landmark and is also listed on the National Register.
            This cultural haven was founded in 1905 and later rebuilt in 1916.
            Bought by the Chicago Park District in 1975,
            this historic building was restored as a historic landmark after a massive community campaign led by the Chicago Park District and historic preservationists.
            South Shore Cultural Center totals 70.84 acres.</item>
        <item>Designed by William Le Baron Jenney in the mid-1800s and enhanced several years later by Jens Jensen,
            Humboldt Park was once the nation\’s greatest public park,
            boasting acres of Prairie-style gardens, grazing animals and a meandering river scene.
            Though the animals are long gone, the park is still a gem among Chicago\'s public green spaces, filled with lagoons,
            tennis courts, an inland beach, a fieldhouse, baseball fields and bike paths.
            Wandering through the area long enough and you\'ll probably come across the Humboldt Park Boathouse,
            an iconic example of the Prairie-style architecture that was made famous by Frank Lloyd Wright.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="addressOfParks">
        <item>201 E Randolph St Chicago IL 60602</item>
        <item>337 E Randolph St Chicago IL 60601</item>
        <item>Bloomingdale Trail Chicago</item>
        <item>at Stockton and LaSalle Drs Chicago</item>
        <item>100 N Central Park Ave Chicago</item>
        <item>6401 S Stony Island Ave Chicago</item>
        <item>337 E Randolph St Chicago IL 60601</item>
        <item>7059 S Shore Dr Chicago</item>
        <item>1400 N Sacramento Ave Chicago</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="hoursOfParks">
        <item>Daily 8am–9pm</item>
        <item>Daily 6am-11pm</item>
        <item>Daily 6am-11pm</item>
        <item>Daily 6am–11pm</item>
        <item>Daily 6am–11pm</item>
        <item>Daily 6am–11pm</item>
        <item>Daily 6am–11pm</item>
        <item>Daily 7am–11pm</item>
        <item>Daily 6am–11pm</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="nameOfRestaurants">
        <item>Lula Cafe</item>
        <item>J.P. Graziano Grocery</item>
        <item>Tzuco</item>
        <item>Birrieria Zaragoza</item>
        <item>avec</item>
        <item>Giant</item>
        <item>Boka</item>
        <item>Oriole</item>
        <item>Galit</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="descriptionOfRestaurants">
        <item>This Logan Square darling has been doing the whole farm-to-table thing long before it was a thing.
            And though Lula hasn\'t resumed indoor or outdoor dining,
            chef-owner Jason Hammel offers an unbelievable to-go menu that allows diners to bring home brunch,
            lunch and the restaurant\'s famous farm dinners.
            Place your order in advance and pick up at Lula\'s nifty carryout window.
            Fair warning: You will be tempted to toss in something sweet from pastry chef Emily Spurlin—just go with it. </item>
        <item>The old school vibe at this corner shop isn\’t manufactured—the Graziano family has been doing its thing here since 1937.
            While it\’s hard to go wrong with any of their sandwiches, the Mr. G ($9.25)—prosciutto, salami and sopressata,
            with biting aged provolone and marinated artichokes tucked into crackly-crisp bread anointed with hot oil and truffle mustard vinaigrette—claims house specialty status for a reason.</item>
        <item>Beyond the whole eating-for-survival thing, what endears so many of us to food on a deeper level is its ability to tell a story.
            In Tzuco\’s quenching ceviche verde, for example, you can almost taste pure, cold Pacific Ocean in pearlescent slivers of hamachi,
            which are paired with three expressions of cactus, a plant that thrives in the most unforgiving locales.
            The prickly flora is served cured, iced and juiced with mint, lime and a whisper of serrano chile.
            Together, the elements sing of Mexico\’s varied bounty.</item>
        <item>Thick handmade tortillas, salsas made to order, cinnamon-laced coffee. You can get all of that here.
            Their only purpose, however, is to accompany this restaurant\’s signature platters of chopped goat meat.
            As opposed to other birrierias, this goat doesn\’t touch a consommé until it\’s plated,
            when some of the tomato-based broth is spooned over it.
            At that point, a good dousing of the restaurant\’s intricate hot sauce, and maybe a squeeze of lime and some onions,
            is all you need for one of the city\’s best goat tacos.</item>
        <item>There are rules when eating at avec. One of them is “No talking about Israel.”
            A few weeks ago I was eating dinner and my friend—not I—was breaking that rule. Loudly.
            The man sitting next to me, whom I did not know but whom I spent the evening less than one inch from,
            leaned into our space and said,
            “What nation are you talking about?”
            This is why you don\’t talk about Israel at avec.</item>
        <item>A framed print of Shel Silverstein\’s poem Me and My Giant hangs on the wall of this ironically named Logan Square restaurant—it\’s tiny,
            sitting only 44 people. But what Giant lacks in space it makes up for in flavor.
            After closing Nightwood in 2015,
            chef Jason Vincent took time off from the Chicago dining scene before opening Giant with partners Ben Lustbader and Josh Perlman in summer 2016.</item>
        <item>While we were driving to dinner at Boka last weekend,
            my dinner date confessed: “All I want to eat for dinner is chicken.”
            “You\’re in luck,” I said. “Lee Wolen is a god of chicken.”
            When the Boka Group overhauled its ten-year old flagship restaurant earlier this winter, it made a few key changes.
            It revamped the space so it\’s unrecognizable from its previous, staid incarnation—now,
            there\’s a huge moss- and plant-covered wall with paintings of elegantly dressed-up animals;
            a bar area that feels like a boisterous brasserie, with dark leather, brick walls and dim lighting;
            and portraits of Bill Murray and Dave Grohl as generals.</item>
        <item>It took some time wandering through River West on an icy,
            blustery night before we finally found the much raved-about Oriole—from industry vets Noah Sandoval,
            Genie Kwon and Aaron McManus.
            The door in the back alley is relatively unmarked, as if the restaurant knows it\’s worth seeking out. And it\’s not wrong.
            Here is a fine diner that gets everything right, right from the start: The moment we entered,
            the host whisked away my jacket and replaced it with a steaming cup of sochu-laced cider.
            It was like she was reading my mind.</item>
        <item>Hummus, falafel, shakshuka, labneh—hell—even pita.
            You will have no doubt already experienced many of the dishes on Galit\’s broad-spectrum Middle Eastern menu.
            But this Lincoln Park newcomer from James Beard award-winning chef Zachary Engel is where you go to revise the standard for how they should taste.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="numbersOfRestaurants">
        <item>+1 773-489-9554</item>
        <item>+1 312-666-4587</item>
        <item>+1 312-374-8995</item>
        <item>+1 773-523-3700</item>
        <item>+1 312-377-2002</item>
        <item>+1 773-252-0997</item>
        <item>+1 312-337-6070</item>
        <item>+1 312-877-5339</item>
        <item>+1 773-360-8755</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="priceOfRestaurants">
        <item>$23 - $45</item>
        <item>$6 - $20</item>
        <item>$23 - $45</item>
        <item>$8 - $20</item>
        <item>$8 - $12</item>
        <item>$20 - $45</item>
        <item>$30 - $80</item>
        <item>$190 - $400</item>
        <item>$65 - $100</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="nameOfHotels">
        <item>Trump International Hotel</item>
        <item>Claridge House</item>
        <item>Thompson Chicago</item>
        <item>LondonHouse Chicago</item>
        <item>The Langham</item>
        <item>Hotel Julian</item>
        <item>Moxy Chicago Downtown</item>
        <item>The Peninsula Chicago</item>
        <item>Virgin Hotels Chicago</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="descriptionOfHotels">
        <item>Get past the 20-foot letters emblazoned on the building and there\’s no denying: This hotel is a stunner.
            Guests beeline to the wellness trifecta on the 14th-floor that includes a 75-foot swimming pool,
            an 11-treatment-room spa with sprawling locker rooms, and a serious fitness center wrapped in windows.
            But even locals come to the 16th-floor rooftop for unparalleled views of the Chicago River and skyline.
            They\'re doing it in a more laid-back atmosphere now though,
            as the two-Michelin-starred Sixteen was replaced with a more casual option in 2018.</item>
        <item>It\'s not easy to find peace and quiet around the Gold Coast,
            but Claridge House somehow manages to provide a calm oasis in the middle of one of Chicago\'s busiest neighborhoods.
            You can thank the hotel\'s fresh renovation,
            which transformed the 165-room property into a relaxing home away from home:
            warm gray walls and light features in the lobby,
            tastefully minimal rooms with cozy throw blankets, and a luxurious spa located on the second floor.
            And when you\'re ready to turn up the energy a few notches,
            you can simply step outside of the hotel to find museums and restaurants filling every street—plus the shores of Lake Michigan just a 0.3 miles away.
            Claridge House truly offers the best of both worlds.</item>
        <item>Sleek with organic accents, the Thompson Chicago hints at Prairie School architectural homage.
            Even the Cityview King has a great view of the skyline, but for a wee upgrade you get Lake Michigan, too.
            There\'s a slightly masculine color scheme of neutrals and rich browns contributes to a sense of ease.
            But the best perk of all?
            You don\'t even have to leave the hotel to eat at one of Chicago\'s best restaurants: Nico Osteria,
            known for seasonal Italian fare.
            Other notable touches include the sleek design, quirky artwork, and great location.</item>
        <item>Set in a landmark building where the Magnificent Mile meets the Chicago River,
            LondonHouse Chicago is all about the views.
            The gold coffered ceiling of the ground floor lobby makes a stunning first impression,
            but the best rooms—the Vista rooms—are in a glass addition featuring floor-to-ceiling windows overlooking the river and the bridges that vault over it.
            Dark wood paneling and framed black-and-white photos lend a slightly masculine tone.
            There\'s a nightclubby restaurant on the 21st floor,
            and a rooftop bar with one of the best views in the city is just one more floor up.
            Buy a glass of Dom Perignon, and you can have the iconic cupola—the topper on the 1923 landmark building, and a popular engagement spot—all to yourself.</item>
        <item>A highlight of any Chicago riverboat architecture tour is Mies van der Rohe\’s last skyscraper—330 North Wabash,
            still commonly referred to as the IBM Building.
            It\’s a paragon of the late International Style:
            a 52-story rectangle of anodized aluminum and bronze glass that is the perfect distillation of corporate might and urban promise.
            To check into the Langham Chicago,
            which has occupied the building\’s first 13 floors since 2013,
            is to step into the story the building tells about the American city.
            You feel like you could be a character in a spy thriller as you pass through the note-perfect midcentury lobby and take the elevator to the elegant second-floor reception area</item>
        <item>Located in the former Atlantic Bank Building on North Michigan Avenue,
            Hotel Julian feels right at home in its prime spot across from Millennium Park—you\'d hardly guess it has only been around since late 2018.
            Named after named after St. Julian, the patron saint of hospitality,
            this 228-room property feels fully modern while retaining some historic touches—you\'ll see the building\'s original brickwork in the lobby,
            for example.The guest rooms are roomy and minimal, with high ceilings and brown leather headboards.
            The color and pizzazz seem to have been reserved for the social spaces: think lime green sofas,
            patterned throw pillows, and jam packed gallery walls.</item>
        <item>Neon-pink light strips punctuate the façade of Moxy Chicago,
            an eight-story Downtown hotel that\'s a bit like a rec-room—for adults.Inside is no less loud,
            with a lobby stuffed to the gills with all manner of aesthetic distractions.
            Reception feels like an extension of the bar; a piñata sits on the tabletop;
            graffiti covers exposed concrete walls; shuffleboard and foosball populate the common space;
            and there\'s even a podcasting booth.
            Food and drink options are limited to two venues: Zombie Taco,
            which dishes out flavorful fare around the clock and includes an outdoor patio as well as a walk-up window for those on-the-go, and Bar Moxy,
            a casual lobby hang with comically titled cocktails that pack a punch.</item>
        <item>Bedrooms at The Peninsula Chicago are large for the downtown area,
            but feel even more spacious thanks to clever ship-cabin cabinetry.
            Indeed, interiors have a yacht-like feel, in both the space-saving design and the burled wood and leather finishes.
            With muted pale-blue and steel-grey tones, the palette nods towards Lake Michigan, while a wall-size,
            hand-embroidered rendering of a chrysanthemum refers to Peninsula\’s Asian roots without feeling too on-the-nose.</item>
        <item>Virgin Hotels Chicago outpost is all about contrasts: It\'s buzzy in public and serene in private,
            and cheeky accents and a cherry-red color scheme contrast with the stately old bank building it calls home.
            At once clubby and retreat-like, there are loads of dining and drinking options: the centerpiece Commons Club,
            the ground-level diner Miss Ricky\'s, and the rooftop bar and lounge, Cerise,
            which has great views of the city from its seasonal patio.
            The library—actually called the Funny Library—next to the second-floor Commons Club bar was curated by the improv group Second City.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="numbersOfHotels">
        <item>+1 (312) 588-8000</item>
        <item>+1 (312) 787-4980</item>
        <item>+1 (312) 266-2100</item>
        <item>+1 (312) 357-1200</item>
        <item>+1 (312) 923-9988</item>
        <item>+1 (312) 346-1200</item>
        <item>+1 (312) 527-7200</item>
        <item>+1 (312) 337-2888</item>
        <item>+1 (855) 946-6600</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="priceOfHotels">
        <item>$260/night</item>
        <item>$175/night</item>
        <item>$125/night</item>
        <item>$100/night</item>
        <item>$278/night</item>
        <item>$185/night</item>
        <item>$160/night</item>
        <item>$399/night</item>
        <item>$128/night</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>